Dr Deepika Chaudhari

SET NET PhD (English)

A-1, 1804, 18th floor, Sai Gaurav building, Sai Chawk, Khadakpada, Kalyan (W) 421301

Contact No.: 09653667560/8655162692

Dipikakolambe3@gmail.com

Drdipikachaudhari79@gmail.com

Professional Synopsis

Over 4 years of teaching experience in domains of Communication Skills and Business

Communication Skills to undergraduate arts, commerce & engineering students.

Qualified the exams like SET and NET respectively in the years 2017 and 2018.

Completed PhD respectively in the year 2020.

The reputable University of Mumbai declared result for Phd in English Literature for the

research on novels and short stories of Manjushree Thapa titled Social and Cultural

Institutions of Nepal in the novels and short stories of Manjushree Thapa under the

supervision of Dr. Shashikant Mhalunkar, B.N.N College, Bhiwandi.

Work Experience

• Worked as 'Lecturer—English' at Jondhale diploma polytechnic college, Dombivli from

June 2014 to May. 2015

• Worked as 'Asst. Professor—English' at B.N.N College of Arts, Science & Commerce,

Bhiwandi from July 2015 to May 2017.

• Worked as 'CHB Lecturer- English' at Muchala Polytechnic College, Thane from

November 2016 to April 2017

• Worked as 'CHB Lecturer - English' at VPM Polytechnic College, Thane from June 2016

to April 2017.

• Worked as 'CHB lecturer English' at B.K. Birla college, Kalyan from June 2019 to March

2020

 Worked as Assistant professor in S. H. Mutha college Kalyan from March 2020 to March 2021

*Currently working in the K.V. Pendharkar College, from March 2022 in the BAMMC Department.

Subjects taught:

Business Communication to FYB.Com

Communication Skills in English to FYBA

Communication Skills in English to First Year diploma Polytechnic

Content Writing, Introduction to Advertising to FYBAMMC

Media Ethics and Laws, Mass Media Research to SYBAMMC

Business Communication to FYBMS and FYBBI

Duties performed:

Conducted lectures on basic grammar, verbal and written communication, Business Communication, Group Discussion and Interview skills, up to First year students of arts, commerce

Evaluated oral and written English skills of students as internal and external examiner

Question paper setting

Professional Qualification

- HSC (Arts) with 67% in 2006 from Birla College, Mumbai Division of Maharashtra
 State Board of Secondary and Higher Secondary Education
- BA (English) with 57% in 2009 from Birla College, University of Mumbai 3. MA
 (English) with 56% in 2011 from RKT College, University of Mumbai 4. B.ed
 (English) with 56% in 2014 from Gurukrupa College, University of Mumbai 5.
 Qualified Maharashtra SET (English) in April 2017
- 6. Qualified NET (English) in July 2018

7. PhD (English) University of Mumbai declared result on 23 January 2020 **Research**

Research done on the novels and short stories of Manjushree Thapa, She is the first woman writer in Nepali English literature. Research titled 'Social and Cultural Institutions of Nepal in the Novels and Short Stories of Manjushree Thapa', under the supervision of Prof. Dr Shashikant Mhalunkar. The basic assumption of this research was to identify Social and Cultural institutions of Nepal in the Thapa's novels and short stories. The study tried to analyze the selected novels and stories to look into issues like migration and diaspora. Thapa has explored the problems of Nepali migrants and touched upon the issues such as social discrimination, man-woman relationship, marriage, religion and politics. This research revealed the social, cultural and political reality of Nepal and an overview of Nepali literature.

Seminars Attended

- UGC Sponsored One Day Interdisciplinary National Seminar on "CULTURAL
 EXPRESSIONS IN HUMANITIES", organized by B.N.N College, Bhiwandi on 15th
 October 2016
- UGC Sponsored Two Day National Conference on "Interpreting Short Stories of the Post 1950s", organized by Department of English of Shri.M.D.Shah Mahila College of Arts and Commerce, Santacruz on 18th and 19th November 2016
- One Day Multidisciplinary National Conference on 'Contemporary Trends in Language, Literature, Feminism & Culture' organized by K. V. Pendharkar College, Dombivli on 25th February 2017
- 4. One Day Interdisciplinary International Conference on "Recent Advances In Languages, Literature And Social Sciences", organized by M.G.E.W Society's CENTER FOR HUMANITIES AND CULTURAL STUDIES, Kalyan (W) in collaboration with NEW MAN INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MULTIDISCIPLINARY STUDIES (UGC approved Journal) on 17th February, 2018.
- 5. One Day Interdisciplinary National Seminar on "An Interdisciplinary Approach

Towards Humanity And Business: Today's Demand Of Progress", organized by MatoshreeSumatiChintamaniTipnis College of Arts and Commerce, Neral on 07th March 2018.

6. One Day Multidisciplinary International Conference on "Emerging Issues in Contemporary Indian: Local and Global Perspectives", organized by Daar-UlRehmat Trust's A.E.Kalsekar Degree college, Mumbra on 17th March 2018.

Papers Presented

- 'Cultural representation in Manjushree Thapa's novel The Tutor of History' at UGC Sponsored One Day Interdisciplinary National Seminar on 'Cultural Expressions in Humanities' organized by B.N.N College, Bhiwandi on 15th October 2016
- 'Journey motif in Manjushree Thapa's Short stories' at the Two-day UGC Sponsored National Seminar on 'Interpreting Short Stories of the Post 1950s' organized by Shri.
 M. D. Shah Mahila College, Santacruz on 18th and 19th November 2016
- 'Nepali-American Woman's experiences in Manjushree Thapa's novel Seasons of Flight' at One Day Multidisciplinary National Conference on 'Contemporary Trends in Language, Literature, Feminism & Culture' organized by K. V. Pendharkar College, Dombivli on 25th February 2017
- 4. One Day Interdisciplinary International Conference on "Recent Advances In Languages, Literature And Social Sciences", organized by M.G.E.W Society's CENTER FOR HUMANITIES AND CULTURAL STUDIES, Kalyan (W) in collaboration with NEW MAN INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MULTIDISCIPLINARY STUDIES (UGC approved Journal), Aurangabad on 17th February, 2018.
- 5. One Day Interdisciplinary National Seminar on "An Interdisciplinary Approach Towards Humanity And Business: Today's Demand Of Progress", organized by Matoshree Sumati Chintamani Tipnis College of Arts and Commerce, Neral on 07th March 2018.

6. One Day Multidisciplinary International Conference on "Emerging Issues in Contemporary Indian: Local and Global Perspectives", organized by Daar-Ul Rehmat Trust's A.E.Kalsekar Degree college, Mumbra on 17th March 2018.

Papers Published

1. 'Cultural representation in Manjushree Thapa's novel The Tutor of History', December

2016 (ISSN: 2348-1390) p 86-89

2. 'Psychological Perspectives on Woman's Alienation in Manjushree Thapa's Seasons of

Flight', February 2018 (ISSN: 2454-5503) p 54-55

3. 'From the Local to Global through Translation: A Reading of Ambai's "In a

Forest, ADeer", VOLUME-VII, ISSUES-1-JANUARY-MARCH-2018 AJANTA (ISSN:

2277-5730) P 150-154

4. 'Depiction of rural Nepal in Manjushree Thapa's Tutor of History', April 2020

Setupublication P 87-95

Books Published

A) FICTION

ANANTPRABHA. Bangalore: Clever Fox Publication, 2021. ISBN: 9789390850761

B) ACADEMIC

MANJUSHREE THAPA IN NEPALI LITERARY MAP. Bangalore: Clever Fox Publication,

2021. ISBN: 9789391537494

Awards and Achievements

• Awarded the secplace at the Inter-Collegiate Street Play Competition at Annual Extension

Work Festival UDAAN: THE FLIGHT OF EXTENSION held in the year

2014 conducted by the University of Mumbai

• Gold medalist in Gandhiyan Study centre exam, 2014

Other Credentials

 $Completed \ Certificate \ Course \ on \ MS-CIT$

Classical Dancer (Bharatnatyam Arrangyatram)

Personal Profile

Cast	OBC (Leva-Patidar)
Nationality	Indian
Date of Birth	13 th January, 1989
Languages known	English, Hindi and Marathi